Christos Dematas

Front End Engineer II

Καλλιθέα

demataschristiano@gmail.com

+30 698 673 5590

Front End Software Engineer, I bring with me over 2.5+ years of valuable professional experience (+2 years of freelance). Throughout my journey, I have been a crucial contributor to numerous company projects, engaging from the initial development phase to successful product launches, and even tackling the inevitable "bug fix Fridays". Now, I am eagerly seeking a stimulating role that will allow me to continue expanding and refining my skills.

Work Experience

Front End Software Engineer

Quality & Reliability S.A. - Αθήνα November 2022 to Present

Quality & Reliability (QnR) dabbles mainly on hellenic government projects.

- Collaboration for development of mainly Hellenic Government projects such as PPC, OAED, MFA.
- Optimized existing software codebase to eliminate unnecessary complexity and achieve increased efficiencies in debugging and maintenance.
- Development of android/ios apps for private sector clients.
- · Aggregated software project knowledge and documentation for future development teams.

Full Stack Software Engineer

Grapevine Digital SA - Αθήνα July 2021 to November 2022

Grapevine Digital is a start-up SAAS company that got created after the integration of giaola and 11888.gr as a maintainer of the said project.

- Implemented decoupling of the existing project through the creation of a REST API and a comprehensive front-end redesign.
- Worked closely with the team to successfully develop the front-end of new projects.
- Maintained, debugged and developed new features for existing codebase.

Education

University in Technical Computer Applications

Hellenic Open University - Απομακρυσμένη Εργασία August 2022 to Present